

Barend Erasmus hirebarend@gmail.com +27 76 654 2813

Date of Birth May 23, 1996 Gender Male

Nationality South African

Address Unit 14, Santa Barbara 63-65 Blaauwberg Road Table View, Cape Town 7439

Languages Afrikaans, English, Spanish

Notice Period 1 Calendar Month

01. Barend Erasmus

I have 8+ years of experience in designing and building systems using Microsoft Azure. My expertise lies in driving scalability, reliability, and availability. I've led multiple projects on the technology front with multi-national teams.

I get a kick out of mentoring others and simplifying complex problems.

02. Experience

Designing and building systems for companies · Certified Microsoft Solutions Architect

Senior Technical Team Lead at Euromonitor International (Pty) Ltd

November 2022 - Present

Senior Software Engineer (Lead) at iKhokha (Pty) Ltd

May 2022 - October 2022 (6 Months)

Technical Team Lead at Flash Mobile Vending (Pty) Ltd

August 2021 - April 2022 (9 Months)

Senior Software Engineer at Media24 (Pty) Ltd

April 2020 - July 2021 (1 Year, 4 Months)

Spent my time as a senior software engineer rearchitecting backend services, migrating them to the cloud, and working on the audio generation for articles. I've also lead a team on the Landbou and Netwerk24 re-platforming project.

Technical Lead at Euromonitor International (Pty) Ltd

April 2019 - March 2020 (1 Year)

Spent my time as a technical lead maintaining and rearchitecting certain aspects of the E-commerce and CMS project with a team of software engineers.

Senior Software Engineer at Euromonitor International (Pty) Ltd

September 2018 - March 2019 (7 Months)

Spent my time as a senior software engineer building microservices in .NET CORE and user interfaces in Angular with CosmosDB, MS SQL Server, and Apache Jena Fuseki. During this time I also assisted with the training and onboarding of software engineers.

Software Engineer at Euromonitor International (Pty) Ltd

March 2016 - August 2018 (2 Years, 6 Months)

Spent my time as a software engineer maintaining the flagship product called Passport, assisting in re-architecting the core caching implementation and migrating web applications to Microsoft Azure.

Full-Stack Software Engineer at Return True (Pty) Ltd

December 2014 - February 2016 (1 Year, 3 Months)

After a month as an intern at Return True, I joined as a full-stack software engineer. My primary project consisted of MVC 4, Web API backend, and an HTML/CSS/JQuery frontend with an MS SQL database. My secondary projects consisted of Android (Java) and C# projects.

Intern Software Engineer at Return True (Pty) Ltd

September 2014 – October 2014 (1 Month)

I joined Return True for a month as an intern software engineer and worked alongside their intermediate and senior software engineers on mobile apps written in Java (Android) and backend applications written in C# (.NET Framework).

03. Certifications

Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Engineer Associate

Dec 2022

Responsibilities for this role include helping stakeholders understand the data through exploration, building and maintaining secure and compliant data processing pipelines by using different tools and techniques. This professional uses various Azure data services and languages to store and produce cleansed and enhanced datasets for analysis.

Microsoft Certified: DevOps Engineer Expert

July 2021

Responsibilities for this role include designing and implementing strategies for collaboration, code, infrastructure, source control, security, compliance, continuous integration, testing, delivery, monitoring, and feedback.

Microsoft Certified: Azure Solutions Architect Expert

June 2021

Responsibilities for this role include advising stakeholders and translating business requirements into designs for secure, scalable, and reliable Azure solutions.

Microsoft Certified: Azure Administrator Associate

May 2021

Responsibilities for this role include implementing, managing, and monitoring identity, governance, storage, compute, and virtual networks in a cloud environment, plus provision, size, monitor, and adjust resources, when needed.

Microsoft Certified: Azure Developer Associate

May 2021

Responsibilities for this role include participating in all phases of cloud development from requirements, definition, and design; to development, deployment, and maintenance; to performance tuning and monitoring.

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

April 2021

Azure Fundamentals certification is an opportunity to prove knowledge of cloud concepts, Azure services, Azure workloads, security and privacy in Azure, as well as Azure pricing and support. Candidates should be familiar with the general technology concepts, including concepts of networking, storage, compute, application support, and application development.

04. Projects

Nano Files

https://nanofiles.io

File Monkey

https://filemonkey.io

05. Education

University of South Africa (Bachelor of Science in Computing)

January 2023 - Present

Jan van Riebeeck High

January 2010 - December 2014